[
  {
    "no": "01",
    "question": "What is Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "A PHP framework",
      "A JavaScript library",
      "A database management system",
      "A web hosting service"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A PHP framework"
  },
  {
    "no": "02",
    "question": "Which command is used to create a new Laravel project?",
    "options": ["laravel new", "create-project", "make-project", "new-laravel"],
    "correctAnswer": "laravel new"
  },
  {
    "no": "03",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'artisan' in Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "To generate code",
      "To handle command-line tasks",
      "To create database migrations",
      "To manage routes"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To handle command-line tasks"
  },
  {
    "no": "04",
    "question": "What is Eloquent in Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "A templating engine",
      "A database management tool",
      "An ORM (Object-Relational Mapping) system",
      "A testing framework"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "An ORM (Object-Relational Mapping) system"
  },
  {
    "no": "05",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'composer' in Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "To manage database migrations",
      "To handle front-end dependencies",
      "To create database tables",
      "To generate code"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To handle front-end dependencies"
  },
  {
    "no": "06",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'middleware' in Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "To define routes",
      "To handle HTTP requests",
      "To manage database migrations",
      "To create authentication systems"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To handle HTTP requests"
  },
  {
    "no": "07",
    "question": "What does MVC stand for in Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "Model View Controller",
      "Model View Component",
      "Most Valuable Contributor",
      "Model View Connect"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Model View Controller"
  },
  {
    "no": "08",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'migration' in Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "To create database tables",
      "To handle front-end dependencies",
      "To define routes",
      "To manage authentication"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To create database tables"
  },
  {
    "no": "09",
    "question": "What is the default database connection used in Laravel?",
    "options": ["SQLite", "MySQL", "PostgreSQL", "MongoDB"],
    "correctAnswer": "MySQL"
  },
  {
    "no": "10",
    "question": "What is the purpose of 'blade' in Laravel?",
    "options": [
      "To handle authentication",
      "To create database migrations",
      "To define routes",
      "To provide a templating engine"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "To provide a templating engine"
  }
]
